Finding Aid for Woman’s Christian Temperance Union, Ann Arbor Chapter records, 1874 and 1877-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Woman’s Christian Temperance Union, Ann Arbor Chapter records 1874, 1877-1979
Woman’s Christian Temperance Union. Ann Arbor Chapter.
2.5 linear feet
86331 Bj 2
Ann Arbor chapter of the Woman’s Christian Temperance Union; Minute books and treasurer’s books of Mary J. Taft Union; secretary’s book of Juvenile Temperance Union, 1877-1885; miscellaneous other records, and motion pictures.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was the gift of the organization and came through Mrs. H. B. Rice (donor no. 4967 ) in 1970.
The record group is open to research.
The Ann Arbor chapter of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union was formed in 1877 and disbanded May 17, 1979.
The Woman’s Christian Temperance Union, Ann Arbor Chapter records consist of minute books and treasurer’s books of Mary J. Taft Union; secretary’s book of Juvenile Temperance Union, 1877-1885; and miscellaneous other records. The records have been arranged into four series: Secretary's books; Treasurer's books; Other Records, and Motion Pictures. The Other Records series includes scattered, correspondence, a letter, June 1884, to the University of Michigan Board of Regents concerning regulation of student drinking, a scrapbook and clippings about the chapter's activities, and miscellaneous.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Juvenile Temperance Union (Mich.); Social reformers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Temperance--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union. Ann Arbor Chapter (Mich.)
Contributors:
Woman's Christian Temperance Union. Mary J. Taft Union.
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.
- Secretary's book
  - 1877-1880 (Box 1)
  - 1883-1889 (Box 1)
  - 1890-1894 (Box 1)
  - 1895-1898 (Box 1)
  - 1898-1901 (Box 1)
  - 1907-1911 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1922-1926 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1950 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1955 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1967 (Box 1)
  - 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - 1972-1979 (Box 1)
  - 1877-1885 of the Juvenile Temperance Union (Box 1)
- Treasurer's book
  - 1893-1902 (Box 2)
  - 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  - 1950-1952 (Box 2)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 2)
  - 1953-1956 (Box 2)
  - 1956-1959 (Box 2)
  - 1959-1962 (Box 2)
  - 1962-1966 (Box 2)
  - 1966-1974 (Box 2)
  - 1974-1979 (Box 2)
- Other records
  - Personal scrapbook of Lulu Bon Rice circa 1930s-1950s (Box 2)
  - Letter June 1874 to University of Michigan Board of Regents concerning regulation of student drinking (Box 2)
  - History of W.C.T.U. movement with special emphasis on Ann Arbor chapter (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous organizational records (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 2)
- Motion Pictures
  - "The Choice is Yours," circa 1950.(Presented by the National Women's Christian Temperance Union; produced by Fred S. Niemann), ca. 25 min. (Box 8)
  - "It's the Brain that Counts," circa 1950 (Produced by Chicago Film Laboratories), ca. 25 min. (Box 8)
  - "The Vicious Circle," circa 1950 (Produced by Fred S. Niemann), ca. 25 min. (Box 8)
  - "Where Does it Get You," circa 1950 (A Century Film production), ca. 15 min. (Box 8)